ankitajain0024@gmail.com Mumbai +918297063939

Professional Summary

4.5 years of diverse industry experience in Build and Release (Devops) with exposure to Software Configuration Management, Installation, deployment, maintaining the applications and environments, maintaining fully automated CI/CD pipelines and automation using shell scripting.

An enthusiatic and high energy driven professional, targeting assignments in Devops with an organization offering challanging work profile in IT industry with following technical skills

Continuous Integration tools-Cloud base Jenkins and Teamcity

SVN, GIT, Bitbucket as version control tools SonarQube as code quality tools

Maven and ANT as Java build tools Shell scripting.

Apache-Tomcat, Web Logic Application servers Ansible as deployment tool

Servicenow, JIRA as incident tracking tools Redhat Linux, UNIX and Windows servers

EXPERIENCE

BNP Paribas India Solutions

Goregaon, Mumbai June 2018 - Present

Devops Support

- Experience using wide variety of Devops tools and technologies such as Jenkins, teamcity, svn, GIT, Maven etc.
- Manages the team providing technical support whenever needed.
- Working in building products in agile methodology, Project Management, SDLC, Software Analysis, Design, Testing and Development Phase.
- Hands on experience in building continuous delivery pipeline
- Hands on experience with agile projects in software development with CI and CD process using different tools like Bitbucket, Artifactory in large engineering Team.

Aug 2017 - April 2018 Release Manager

- Managing quarterly release cycle containing 10-15 projects.
- Report Release health directly to Executive Committee through release status meetings.
- Schedule and facilitate all Release Follow-up and Management meetings.
- Publish Release status through weekly meetings.
- o Sending elaborated MOM after every release follow-up meeting.
- Work with multiple IT development Teams to create and manage a detailed release installation plan.
- Manage post release implementation support and report status and collect release feedback from stakeholders for continuous improvement.

Wells Fargo India Solutions Pvt Ltd

Gachibowli, Hyderabad July 2016 - July 2017

Senior Analyst

- Performed build and deployment to various environments (Dev. QA and Production) using ANThill Pro.
- Created Game plans and executing them for different Banking application for Batch and infra installs
- Performed and maintained the load balancing on different servers using F5 load balancer.
- Worked as a Middleware request Handler, and performed patching for different test and production servers.

Accenture Services Pvt Ltd

Hi-Tech City, Hyderabad Dec 2013 - June 2015

Software Engineer

- Automated the builds and releases in all the environments through Jenkins.
- Worked effectively on SVN/CVS repository maintenance (SVN tags, branches).
- Performed debugging in P1 calls and performed the Emergency Releases as needed.
- o Performed Maven and Ant builds, incorporating auto increment of artifact versions for each build.
- Prepared Unix/Linux Shell Scripts to Build, Migrate and Deploy code on DEV/TEST/PRODUCTION Servers.
- Efficiently Handled Java Exceptions and Errors while building the war files and Co-ordinating with Developers.
- Worked on versioning and streamlining the code base using SVN and CVS version Control, maintained the code base, provided the access to users, and created new repositories and projects.

EDUCATION

Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University

Delhi, India